Sidimar Gobbo

UX/UI Designer

About

I'm Brazilian UX/UI Designer, I am currently working as UX/UI designer in Ireland in leading edge school management software.

My main activities are transform what the final users needs in concept and visual design. To do that I use design thinking to understand better what the user really needs and before starting creating a high visual concept I prototype and test to validate the ideas and concepts.

Contact

089 458 7676

sidimar@gmail.com
My portfolio: sidimar.com

Skills & Expertise

User Experience Design & (Analysis, scenarios, wireframes, prototypes)
Interface design (Lo-Fi - High Fi - mockups)
Information Design (Typography, grid design, creating visual hierarchy)
Standards based, semantic (X)HTML and CSS, basic knowledge of javascript

Design Thinking - Paper Prototyping - User Interface Design - Sketch App - Illustrator - Photoshop - Scrum - WordPress

Experience

UX / UI Designer at Learning Data

Jul 2013 - Present - Learning Data - Dublin

Majority of work in Senior User Experience Designer for school management software:

- Transform what the final users needs in concept and visual design.
- Design thinking to understand better what the user really needs
- Prototype and test to validate the ideas and concepts before a high visual concept.
- Designed UX for a school management platform for student, teachers, parents, school staff using design thinking and prototype.
- Designed UX for the admin tool to manage users, groups, homework, school notice, etc.
- Developed to be responsive platform and cross browser.
 Developed for tablets and phone.
- Worked closely with users to inform and educate about UX best practices.
- Redesigned and applied modern concept to old products.

http://www.learningdata.ie - http://www.schoolbag.ie

Web Designer / UI Designer at Ci&T

jan 2010 - Apr 2013 - CI&T Software

- Working on Drupal applications as a support team for websites to Johnson and Johnson, consumer products
- USA and Canada:
- Assessment, understanding and resolution of issues opened by stakeholders and/or QA team.
- Solve issues with HTML, CSS and Jquery inside Drupal.
- Leading a development team with 10 people inside support team. Working on Drupal application development team for Centrum website to Pfizer, USA:
 - Front-end developer, taking mockups in PSD and transforming in HTML, CSS inside Drupal.
 - Working on Microsoft Share Point application development team for Johnson and Johnson, USA IT team:
- Designed blog CEO Johnson and Johnson.

- Developed HTML, CSS to be responsive platform and cross browser.
- Developed UX for tablets and phone.
- Designed wireframes using Balsamiq.

Web Designer / UI Designer

Dec 2007 - Jan 2010 Webcompany

As a hybrid a designer, I worked on a variety of web projects for local and national clients like 3M. Interpreting designed layouts, creating original concepts, production, and webmaster tasks were all my responsibility.

Worked close with users to validated briefings and concepts for website, ecommerces, huge campaigns and quick campaigns.

Designed wireframes, mockups and and final conceptions, validating the ideas with clients and team to generate more valuable and understanding for whole project.

Motion Designer | Web Designer

jun 2006 - sep 2007 Pássaro Azul | Fielder

Majority of work in motion designer in a web agency:

- Designed flash animation for Bayer animal
- Videos / animations how to interaction manual.
- Designed flash websites, animation.
- Migration of portals (Industries and Energy) 3M Brazil.

Education

Universidade Paulista / UNIP

Bachelor's Degree, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design, 2007 - 2009

Universidade São Judas Tadeu

Associate's Degree, Advertising and Marketing, 2005 - 2006

Grade: Social Communication

English Language Academy (ELA)

English Language and Literature, General, 2013 - 2013

Grade: Upper Intermediate

Activities and Societies: Conversation, Grammar

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency)

Portuguese (Native)

Independent Coursework

Agile Meets Design Thinking Design Thinking for Innovation

Volunteer Experience | UX-Designer at SpunOut.ie

October 2013 - October 2013

Created a solution for mobile version.

Projects

Python Jobs Ireland - September 2015 to Present

Find or post Python related jobs available in Ireland for free and without having to register.